[snorts]
Thank you. Appreciate you guys waiting
and I apologize.
>> Thank you.
I'd [snorts] like to ask you
why.
>> We're in the business of winning
football games. And to win football
games, you got to be a great team. And
great great teams have people from all
over the place that come together.
That's why football is so special. I
mean, you look at that locker room and
what people have gone through to get to
to this point in their career on this
particular team.
Uh it's a beautiful thing, man. It's
really, really powerful. Really awesome.
[snorts]
>> Incredible. Incredible. Spoon had a
phenomenal game. Um affected the
quarterback, made the play on the ball.
Um you know, we haven't blissed him that
much this year. He hasn't made that many
plays on the quarterback. Not for a lack
of wanting to on his end, but uh called
his number today. He made it happen. So,
he's a he's a tremendous player.
[snorts]
>> Yeah, we would not be uh having this
press conference right now if Leslie
wasn't a Seahawk. He was um the first
person I called when we got the job. and
uh hopefully I made it very clear to him
that we needed him and he's just he's uh
just a great compliment to my skill set,
to my personality. He's he's such a
great connector with the player. He's
such a great communicator. He calls our
bluff when we're full of crap on defense
when we do stupid stuff and game
planning, which happens probably too
much than we more than we want.
>> But, uh he's been he's been he's been
tremendous.
We love Clint. He's done a great job. I
haven't thought about it yet. So, think
about that later.
>> Oh, [sighs] man. Um,
I think um
I think the one of the great things
about our team is that we grow together
and uh that's something that like that's
part of my life that's it's been a
journey. You know, it hasn't always been
um my faith hasn't always been strong.
You know, you have doubts, you have it's
kind of a roller coaster ride. And over
the last few years, it's been um
really strengthened, you know, and and
you see what our our players do and John
what Jonathan Rainey does every day and
brings people together. Um it's a it's a
journey that we're in together, you
know, and and it's empowering and uh
it's inspiring to uh to pursue that part
of your life that's so so important.
[snorts]
>> Yeah.
Yeah, I'm incredibly happy for him. He's
he's played great football for us all
year. Um just just plays the right way,
man. Just played so violently um
relentlessly. I mean, even like the sack
was on a counter, you know. Um and then
got the ball out, which was something we
needed to do to win the game.
>> Coach, talk about
obstacles.
You know, I I was just spending more
time with Sam on all these interviews.
It's like Sam doesn't care about the
obstacle. Like you like everyone's made
a a narrative of this guy of like
everyone is they they have tried to put
a story and a label on who he is as a
person, who he is as a quarterback. He
does not care. Okay? He he just is the
same guy every day since he shows up.
He's so steadfast. He's a great
teammate. the the teammates, his
teammates love him. All he's done since
he's walked in the door has just been a
tremendous player on our football team
and a tremendous leader who is the same
guy every day. And that's who he is and
that's how we need to talk about him
moving forward.
>> Honestly, no. It's I I like it's
when you talk about like when you talk
about stacking and stacking wins, which
is one of our core philosophies,
you have to believe and have faith in
the power of doing that over the course
of time. So, you could really take any
element of our team and you can kind of
go back to that philosophy and like our
run game is a great example. You know,
everybody was talking about a run game
at the beginning of the season, but we
just stuck to it, kept attacking in the
details. Um takeaways is something how
you affect the court. It's always
something, right? there's always some
part of your team that you're trying to
attack and improve on, but if you stick
to the process and um and the process is
right, you know, then then the results
will get to where you want. But I think
what you saw today is just the the end
point of a team that has been dedicated
to become this team since we walked in
the door in April. And it started with
our offseason program. It started then
it went to training camp and how they
handled the offseason. And uh we just
did it week by week.
Yeah, I'm really happy for Ken. Um,
played a tremendous game. Our offensive
line played really well. Uh, our tight
ends, our rece, everyone really
dedicated themselves to the run game
today, which is something we had to get
going, um, to really control the game.
And, uh,
and I think this is, you know, one of
the best versions of Ken that we've, you
know, up to this point. That is another
example, right, of you know, him and
Sharps had did, you know, did such a
great job throughout the season playing
off one another. Sharps goes down. Um,
which I mean, he deserves a massive
shout out, Zach Charbonet, what he's
done for our football team, but Ken just
keep attacking, you know, and keep
stacking all those things. I mean, this
is a system that it takes a lot of reps
to feel like to feel how to run the, you
know, the zone plays and um, you know,
you just keep stacking those plays and
then you start to play more decisively
and then, uh, those runs starts to pop.
>> Sorry, can you repeat that?
>> I don't know if there's a right or wrong
way, but we're going to have a lot of
fun tonight. Was this [snorts]
the successful dominant defensive
performance tonight?
>> Yeah, we won the game.
>> I love answering this question because
Jod's Jod's been
phenomenal since the day that I
interviewed for the job. You know, I
just I'm I think vividly of um our
conversation we had in Baltimore and I
just loved hearing her vision for the
team and what she wanted to create for
our city and our community and our and
our football team and our franchise. And
that was um really inspiring because it
was I felt it was aligned with what we
wanted to create too and what we how we
wanted to build our program. And man um
when you're aligned on that vision um
it's a it's a fun ride. you know,
sometimes it's not a tough one, but
especially last year, you know, as we're
kind of going through the fog of some
things, she had such a great perspective
on everything. Um, kept us together. Uh,
always, you know, back John and I on
some of the tough decisions we had to
make and it lets you make those
decisions when you know she's in your
corner. So, I'm really happy for her.
What does it take to be the first coach?
What kind of coordination does that
take?
>> Well, I'm I'm glad you asked that
because it's it really is about our
staff, you know, filling in all those
areas that lets you do both jobs, you
know. So, um I think we've gotten to a
point on defense where it's like, look,
I'm saying the words on Sundays, but we
know what we're going to call. we know
why we're going to call it. They've
helped build it. Um they've they've
handled all the details throughout the
week that let me do head coaching stuff.
Leslie Frasier deserves a massive shout
out on that front. AD is a tremendous
defensive coordinator. Um I mean, you
just go right down the list on our staff
of like what they contribute to the game
plan and how we call games throughout
the game. Um it's not just like me on
the on the on the headset just deciding
what we're doing from play to play.
There's a lot of feedback. there's a lot
of um kind of recalibration as games go
in order to make adjustments and um it
just it takes a lot of a lot off my
plate and uh it's what I think that's
what shows uh with the product on the
field.
>> I think it took so long but
so much detail that goes into this.
>> Oh, like historically?
>> Yes.
>> Oh, I'm not I don't know. This is this
is my experience, you know. It's taken
us two years to get to this point.
>> Yeah, you got it. [laughter]
>> [clears throat]
>> We have a lot of respect for the
Patriots, but the answer to that is no.
I mean, when we said we want to keep it
about us, you know, you got to back that
up with your actions and I think that's
what we've done. And um we respected our
opponent. They're a heck of an opponent.
But um we're really happy for our guys
and our and the twelves in our
community. can't wait to bring the
trophy back home. Um,
that's what we're thinking about. That's
and that's what we've talked about the
whole process, too.
>> [clears throat]
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. That sounds pretty cool. Sounds
like a lot of fun. And I was just
telling Dave, you know, it's like
throughout the NFC ch you're not
thinking about the Super Bowl. You're
just doing everything you possibly can
to win that game to help your team win.
And we felt the same way the last two
weeks for the Super Bowl. Haven't really
thought about what the celebration's
going to be like. But now that they were
there, it's going to be pretty awesome.
Uh, look, this is this is why this is
like this is why you coach. This is why
um you want to do it at this level
because you can't you have the
opportunity to bring the twelves, the
people, our community together, our
players. Let them let them feel what it
feels like to like the reward of being
on this team and be champions. Um that's
what fires you up like it, you know,
that's that's just what you get you so
excited and that's what makes you so
proud of our team and um for us to be
able to do it for our community and our
team is um uh doesn't get any better
than this. Mike,
>> you talked about the fans.
>> Oh, it was incredible. Yeah, it felt
well,
with all due respect, it's not Lumen
Field, okay, with our with our twelves,
but we had I don't know what the ratio
was, but it was it was uh it was an
impressive showing by the twelves. And
they I mean, that's that uh provided a
lot of energy. You know, they had to be
on silent cadence the whole game where,
you know, a lot of times we weren't on
silent on offense. So, operationally
that that puts you behind the eightball,
which is what uh some of the advantage
you have playing at home. So, um, Phils
deserve a ton of credit tonight cuz they
brought it.
>> Well, uh, John deserves a lot of credit
to that process. You know, it's kind of
uncharted waters that you have to
navigate and, uh, you know, to the
outside eye, it probably seemed like it
happened fast, but he did a great job of
guiding us through all those decisions.
Jody was right there supporting what we
needed to do. Um, we're on record with
it. Clint had a relationship with him.
There's a lot of people in our building
that knew Sam, um, that, you know, could
vouch for who he was as a person. The
tape backed it up. I think people made
too big of a deal of him of like the
last two games in the season, which I
thought was just dumb. Like, watch the
whole season. The guy played great all
year. He came into Lumen and beat us.
Um, they won like 14 games. So,
um,
Sam knew he or I mean, uh, Clinton knew
he could do the stuff that we want him
to do in our in our in our offense. And
then let's rock and roll.
>> Yep.
Well, that's who we were all season. And
uh you know, where does the credit go?
It goes to everybody. You know,
everybody decided they want to that they
wanted to create this type of team and
they decided they're going to do the
things necessary to make it come to
life. And it takes that takes a lot of
trust. It takes a lot of buy in. It
takes a lot of faith. Um,
and it shows you like the people on, you
know, just responsible for bringing
these guys in the building. I mean, with
kind of like the the like-minded of of
uh how they want to operate. I mean, how
about Jax? Like the guy's an absolute
stud. He's the offensive player of the
year. I don't know what his stats were
today, but he affected the game. I know
that. And to have that type of mentality
he's had all game. There's been some
games this year that he hasn't had, you
know, a trillion yards and a bunch of
touchdowns, but um for what he does for
our football team affects the game in a
large, you know, in a in a big way. And
I don't think and our and I'm glad that
he won the award because that's that's
what shows for it, you know, and he's
just incredible teammate as well.
>> What impressed you most about
>> Cooper is an absolute force multiplier.
um an absolute stud of a person, stud of
a teammate. Uh this should cement him in
the Hall of Fame in my opinion. I mean,
Super Bowl MVP, two-time champion,
um all-time great teammate.
Uh man,
I think the other thing that with with
Coupe is like he just the way he's
helped our program and how we build what
we do from day to day is um not talked
about enough. You know, he's got he's
got a great perspective. I'd be an idiot
not to listen to him. You know,
sometimes we don't do what he wants, but
definitely listen to him.
>> Last question.
>> Yeah. It's funny. It's like you don't
have expectations. You You want to hit
your daily goals. And we knew at the
beginning of the season we needed to
become a championship team for us to
compete for a championship. And so what
were you going to do on a daily basis to
make that come to life? And that's what
we tried to do. And as the season
started to kind of declare itself and we
kept stacking wins uh you knew we had a
like for you know you just want to go
goal by goal. So you know try to let's
get let's do absolutely what we can to
get to the playoffs. Let's try to win
our division. let's try to create as
many home games as possible and let's go
from there. And so I think having that
mindset allows you to get to a point
like this so you don't kind of um you
know you got to keep first things first
and keep it in perspective. But uh guys
have been awesome. Yeah, it's a special
group.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Thank you for your patience.